<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sam Pizzey</title><link>https://pizzey.me/</link><description>Recent content on Sam Pizzey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:33:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pizzey.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adventures in PHP Static Analysis with Psalm</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/adventures-in-php-static-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:33:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/adventures-in-php-static-analysis/</guid><description>I learned recently of Psalm, the open source static analysis tool for PHP released by Vimeo. And then I did a happy dance, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good free SAST tool for PHP for a while.
So the next thing I wanted to discover - is it any help for finding vulnerabilities? And the answer looks to be yes. It has a taint analysis mode, is configurable with custom sinks/sources via plugins and can output the taint graph for us as well as reports in SARIF for other tools to consume (ie.</description></item><item><title>How I Hack PHP Apps (Now)</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/how-i-hack-php-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 23:38:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/how-i-hack-php-apps/</guid><description>I seem to end up spending a lot of my time looking for vulnerabilities in PHP applications. Until fairly recently, my process for this mostly consisted of reading the code (duh), navigating either manually or via Github&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly-good References feature. I used to sometimes import large projects into an IDE for this functionality, which I&amp;rsquo;m glad I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do anymore.
Along with this I make quite heavy use of ripgrep and phpgrep to assist in finding what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://pizzey.me/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 02:05:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/contact/</guid><description>If you need to contact me, the best way is to email me at sam@pizzey.me.
It&amp;rsquo;s also fine to ping me on Twitter if it&amp;rsquo;s something short &amp;amp; casual.</description></item><item><title>Exploiting an 'Unexploitable' SquirrelMail Bug for File Disclosure</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/exploiting-an-unexploitable-squirrelmail-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:44:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/exploiting-an-unexploitable-squirrelmail-bug/</guid><description>If you read most introductory material on exploiting PHP unserialize() calls, you find the same basic pattern: find a call to unserialize() that takes user input, then find an object available that uses a magic method, instantiate one of these objects and use it to start calling other code until you can do something bad.
But what if you find such a call in an application that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any magic methods available?</description></item><item><title>Protecting from the CPanel Ransomware That Doesn't Exist Yet</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/protecting-from-the-cpanel-ransomware-that-doesnt-exist-yet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 17:11:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/protecting-from-the-cpanel-ransomware-that-doesnt-exist-yet/</guid><description>Ransomware just ain’t what it used to be. From the now-relatively-Paleolithic Cryptolocker until today we’ve seen the criminals who run these operations evolve to meet the responses brought against them - from offering free decryption if you infect others, to exploiting insecure MongoDB instances they have shown they’re totally willing to find new avenues to get an edge in this lucrative business.
One thing we haven’t seen a lot of though is ransomware targeting website hosting environments.</description></item><item><title>Honeypotting for the Lazy: Weekend Fishing for Router Bots</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/honeypotting-for-the-lazy-weekend-fishing-for-router-bots/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 17:05:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/honeypotting-for-the-lazy-weekend-fishing-for-router-bots/</guid><description>Recently I decided that I wanted to do a bit more malware analysis. I have a reverse engineering background of sorts, so I wasn’t so concerned with the mechanics of analysing the malware as I was with the question of how do I actually find a sample to analyse that is interesting to me and answers some sort of actual question, rather than purely being a learning exercise?
This happened to be a day or so after the Netgear vulnerability affecting their consumer routers was released to the public and gave me a question to answer - would the IoT botnet authors add support for this vulnerability to their bots?</description></item><item><title>No, I didn't try to break Companies House</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/no-i-didnt-try-to-break-companies-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 17:00:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/no-i-didnt-try-to-break-companies-house/</guid><description>I have a tendency to take a joke too far.
The most recent example of this would be yesterday in IRC, where I was discussing with a few friends what I should name my new company. Being a business to business consultancy, and mostly a one-man operation, the name isn’t that important, but I wanted something with a bit of personality. And I asked:
&amp;lt;Mopman&amp;gt; Is there anything stopping me from registering ; DROP TABLE &amp;#34;Companies&amp;#34;;-- Ltd as a company name?</description></item><item><title>Three leaks users numbers via web service</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/three-leaks-users-numbers-via-web-service/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 16:48:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/three-leaks-users-numbers-via-web-service/</guid><description>OK, so you can file this one under &amp;ldquo;annoying, but not the end of the world&amp;rdquo;.
Three, like most mobile providers, has a mobile application that comes installed on your phone if you buy one from them, or you can download separately if you wish. It mostly replicates a limited subset of the MyThree website, allowing you to view your recent invoices, whether you are eligible for an upgrade, etc.</description></item><item><title>Never let it be said that I waste time...</title><link>https://pizzey.me/posts/never-let-it-be-said-that-i-waste-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:41:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pizzey.me/posts/never-let-it-be-said-that-i-waste-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>A friend of mine recently shared the following on Facebook:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>